Rick Vermeil

Frontend Software Engineer

Erie, CO 80516 (610) 202-1418 rickv85@gmail.com Portfolio GitHub LinkedIn

As a former marketing content manager and product owner, I developed an expertise in project management, web content management and leading a development team in a Scrum / Agile workflow. Through this experience, I gained a high level of user empathy which drives me to create the most intuitive software that I possibly can.

SKILLS

Languages / Frameworks: React, Next.js, JavaScript, TypeScript, CSS3, Sass, Tailwind, HTML5, SQL, Node.js Systems / Practices: Software Development, Object Oriented Programming, UI/UX Development and Design, Web Development, Test Driven Development, Git, GitHub, Redux, Figma, REST API, Agile Methodologies, CI / CD

PROJECTS

Backcountry Bookings | Repo | 4/2023 | 7-person full stack project team | 14-day timeframe

Tech: React, TypeScript, Rails, Ruby, Sass, CSS, HTML, Cypress, Google Maps API, AWS S3 Bucket, Git, GitHub

- Worked with a full-stack team to create a US National Park campground search and review platform.
- Awarded first place in Turing's "Demo Comp" by a panel of judges in the software industry.
- Managed the development process as the product manager of this project.

Ride Ready | Repo | 3/2023 | Solo project | 6-day timeframe

Tech: React, JavaScript, Sass, CSS, HTML, Cypress, Strava OAuth2.0 API, Git, GitHub

Implemented OAuth2.0 authentication to log a Strava user in and utilize their ride data to calculate the service life remaining on their mountain bike suspension based on manufacturer recommendations.

Lav Link | Repo | 2/2023 | 4-person frontend project team | 10-day timeframe

Tech: React, JavaScript, Redux, Sass, CSS, HTML, Cypress, REST API, Google Maps API, Git, GitHub

Constructed a React app with Redux, designed to help a user find a restroom near their location that fits their unique needs by creating filters for unisex, ADA-accessible and restrooms with changing tables.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance Frontend Developer - Self-Employed, Erie, CO - April 2023 to Present

- Leveraging prior marketing experience and Next.js 13 for SEO benefits, currently building a custom designed, highly responsive website with a focus on elegant mobile display for a professional photographer. Utilizing a mix of client-side and server-side rendering to optimize performance and search engine rankings.
- Developed a WordPress-based website tailored for another professional photographer, integrating a purchased theme and applying custom CSS code to meet specific design aesthetics.

Content Marketing Manager / Product Owner - Bestop Inc, Louisville, CO - July 2020 to August 2022

- Led a team of software developers as a Product Owner of a multi-brand e-commerce website production project. Increased project efficiency while reducing spend by over 30%.
- Managed and created all e-commerce website content via WordPress and BigCommerce.

Marketing Specialist - Bestop Inc, Louisville, CO - November 2013 to July 2020

- Coordinated and managed budgets for 80+ consumer and trade events per year.
- Planned and successfully executed a high profile trade show exhibit (avg. \$500k project) for 5 years.
- Coordinated 40+ photo and video shoots per year, creating all marketing assets for product merchandising.

EDUCATION

Front-End Software Engineering - Turing School of Software and Design, Denver, CO Apr 2023

Bachelor's of Science, Business / Marketing - West Chester Univ. of PA, West Chester, PA May 2010